Feeling all beat by 6 PM.
[The Takao-san Hour
Smile!
Is that Good?]
♪♪｢夕方６時は ｸﾞﾀﾞｸﾞﾀﾞ｣
Virgins tend to be timid.
♪♪｢やっぱり どうでもよきかな｣
Getting all bitchy by 6 PM.
♪♪｢夕方６時は ｸﾞｽﾞｸﾞｽﾞ
明日も どうでもよきかな｣
[The "Good?" Middle Aged Corps:
Mako          Mansion          Ken]
Still gonna be a virgin tomorrow.
(拍手)
♬｢This is a pen これはﾍﾟﾝです｣
Kore wa pen desu.
This is a pen.
♪♪(多毛)｢そんなの 見れば
わかるっつってんだろうが！｣
No shit, Sherlock!
♬｢Give me money 予算を上げて｣
Yosan wo agete.
Give me money!
♪♪｢今どき４対３なんて ｳﾁぐらい｣
We're the only ones using 4:3 in this day and age.
After all these years, the costs haven't changed!
♪♪｢何年やっても お値段据え置き｣
♪♪｢謝る気もないのに
ごめんなさい｣
Apologizing when you don't even mean it.
♪♪｢ｼﾞｰﾌﾟがきたら ｷﾞﾌﾞ ﾐｰ ﾁｮｺ！｣
Going "give me chocolate" when a jeep shows up.
♪♪｢笑ってよきかな
ｸﾞｽﾞｸﾞｽﾞｽﾊﾟｰｷﾝ！ ｲｴ～ｲ！｣
Laugh away! Bitchin' sparking! Yay!
♪♪｢来世があるから｣
There's always the next life.
♪♪｢よきかなろ｣
So it's all good!
♪♪｢ﾌﾟﾛｼﾞｪｸﾄ Ｘ｣
Coming straight up!
Tomoro Taguchi!
♪♪｢田口ﾄﾓﾛｦ｣
♬｢よきかな よきかな｣
It's all good. It's all good.
Tomoro Taguchi!
♪♪｢田口！｣
♪♪｢ﾄﾓﾛｦ｣
(拍手)
いったん ＣＭで～す｡
We'll take a commercial break now.
["Shocked by the Phone"]
♪♪～
こんばんは｡
こんばんは！
Good evening.
Good evening!
今日も 暑かったですね｡
It sure was warm today.
そうですね！
Sure was!
もしかして 雨も降った？
Did it rain by any chance?
そうですね！
Sure did!
両方 言っときゃ大丈夫でしょ｡
Mention both and I've covered all the bases.
そうですね！
Sure have!
Since we dubbed this in April.
だって このｱﾌﾚｺやってんの
４月だも～ん｡
そうですね！
Sure did!
結野です｡ よろしくお願いします｡
We have Ketsuno here.
It's a pleasure.
(結野)よろしくお願いします｡
かわいい！
The pleasure is all mine.
え～と それじゃ 昨日の
小栗旬之助君からのご紹介｡
Well then...
So yesterday, we introduced Shunnosuke Oguri-kun.
150話で １ｶｯﾄだけ
出てきた以来ですね｡
He hasn't made an appearance since a scene in episode 150.
今をときめくｽｰﾊﾟｰｱｲﾄﾞﾙ
寺門お通ちゃんです｡ どうぞ｡
Here's the red-hot super idol, Otsu Terakado-chan!
Come on down.
(拍手)
多毛さん 今度 ようやく➡
Tamo-san, I've finally put out a CD.
私のＣＤが出ることに
なったんﾃﾞｽﾚｰｽ｡
へえ～ 今まで出てなかったんだ？
Huh, you've never released one before.
ええ ｱﾆﾒの中では ﾊﾞﾝﾊﾞﾝ
出てるって設定なんですけど➡
Yes.
In the anime, they make it sound like I'm releasing single after single,
ﾘｱﾙなところでは
放送後 苦情がきたり➡
but in real life, we get all kinds of complaints after I perform.
そもそも 歌詞が➡
The lyrics consist of censored words to begin with...
放送禁止用語ばっかりの
内容なんで➡
The big honchos like Ani**** are always bending over for others.
ｱﾆﾌﾟ… をはじめ どこも偉い人が
および腰になっちゃって｡
どういう形式で発売するかって➡
The staff keeps handing off the job of deciding how to release the CD.
関係各社
責任のたらい回しの末…｡
これ はっといて｡
Let's move on.
Well, you've finally released a CD,
まあまあ… あの
せっかく ＣＤ出したんだし➡
so let's drop the risky talk.
危ない話は 置いといて…｡
それじゃ お友達の紹介を…｡
So let's introduce your friend...
え～っ!?
What?!
いや ちょっと…
早くないですか？
Isn't it a little early?
We haven't even done the hundred person survey yet.
まだ 100人ｱﾝｹｰﾄとか何も…｡
(多毛)久しぶりに ｵｰﾌﾟﾆﾝｸﾞで➡
We sang during the opening for the first time in a while,
歌っちゃったから
もう 尺 余ってなくてさ｡
so we're out of time.
そうですね！
Sure are!
て 何なの!?
そこ そうですねなの？
What the hell?!
You're okay with that?!
使いどころ 間違ってない？
Isn't that the wrong time to agree?!
そうですね！
Sure is!
ふざけんな～!!
Don't give me that shit!
そうですね！
Sure thing.
♪♪～
♪♪(お通)｢１ ２ ３ ﾌｫｰｸﾀﾞﾝｽ！｣
♪♪｢夏の日ざし浴びて
靴紐 結んだら｣
♪♪｢さあ 出かけよう ﾜﾝﾀﾞﾌﾙﾜｰﾙﾄﾞ｣
♪♪｢毎朝の牛乳 骨粗しょう症対策｣
♪♪｢ねえ みつこさん
今日 朝ご飯食べたっけ｣
♪♪｢ﾊﾞﾊﾞﾊﾞﾊﾞｰﾝ ﾊﾞﾊﾞ ﾊﾞｯｼｭ｣
♪♪｢お前の ﾊﾞｱちゃん
お前の ﾊﾞｱちゃん｣
お前の ﾊﾞｯｼｭ履いてたぞ｣
♪♪～
♪♪｢ﾊﾞﾊﾞﾊﾞﾊﾞｰﾝ ﾊﾞﾊﾞ ﾊﾞｯｼｭ｣
♪♪｢ﾊﾞﾊﾞﾊﾞﾊﾞｰﾝ｣
♪♪｢お前の ﾊﾞｱちゃん｣
(みんな)ﾊﾞﾊﾞﾊﾞﾊﾞ ﾊﾞｯｼｭ！
♪♪｢お前の ﾊﾞｱちゃん
お前の ﾊﾞｯｼｭ履いてたぞ｣
バ！
♪♪｢ﾊﾞﾊﾞﾝ ﾊﾞﾊﾞﾝ ﾊﾞﾊﾞﾝ｣
♪♪｢ﾊﾞ ﾊﾞﾊﾞﾝ ﾊﾞﾊﾞﾝ ﾊﾞﾊﾞﾝ｣
今日は みんな
私のｺﾝｻｰﾄに来てくれて➡
Everybody, thank you so poop for coming to my concert today!
本当に ありがとうきびｳﾝｺ！
(みんな)とうきびｳﾝｺ～!!
それじゃ 名残惜しいけど➡
Though it pains me, this will be the last song.
最後の１曲
いきたいと思いまｽﾙﾒ｡
曲は もちろん
『お前の母ちゃん …人だ』！
Of course, I'll be singing "Your Mom's a BLEEP"!
♪♪～
♪♪｢あなたのﾎｸﾛ
少し色素が うすいのね｣
Your mole looks a little off-color.
Ne-Ne-Ne-Ne-Necromancer!
(みんな)ﾈﾈﾈﾈ ﾈｸﾛﾏﾝｻｰ！
ありがとうございました
お気をつけてお帰りくださいませ｡
Thank you very much!
Please be careful on your way home!
(たかちん)いや～
今日もｱﾂかったね 新ちゃん｡
Wasn't that crazy, Shin-chan?
やっぱり お通ちゃんのﾗｲﾌﾞは
最高だね｡
Otsu-chan's concerts are the best.
会場が ひとつになる
あの一体感は➡
Nothing can replace the sense of unity in a concert hall.
なにものにも 代えがたいよ｡
(軍曹)惜しむらくは 神曲➡
If I had to find something wrong,
『お前のじいちゃん
自転車立ちこぎしてた』が➡
it'd be their use of an acoustic version of the classic,
ｱｺｰｽﾃｨｯｸﾊﾞｰｼﾞｮﾝに
なっていたことかな｡
"Your Grandpa Stands Too Much When He's Pedaling."
ｱﾚﾝｼﾞもいいけど やっぱり
原曲が聴きたかったね ﾎﾞｸは｡
The arrangement wasn't bad, but personally, I'd have preferred the original.
神曲 『お前のばあちゃん
お前のﾊﾞｯｼｭ履いてた』も➡
And for the classic, "Your Granny's Wearing Your Basketball Shoes,"
客席に ﾏｲｸを振って➡
they turned the mic to the audience so we couldn't hear Otsu-chan singing.
お通ちゃんの歌声が
聴こえなかったね｡
Even if they wanted the audience to feel like part of the performance,
ﾗｲﾌﾞならではの 観客との一体感を
演出するためとはいえ➡
実に残念だったよ｡
おい！
it was rather unfortunate.
Hey, cut the griping, people!
ｸﾞﾁｸﾞﾁ言ってんじゃねえぞ ﾃﾒｴら！
ﾗｲﾌﾞにはﾗｲﾌﾞのよさ
ＣＤにはＣＤのよさがあんだよ！
Concerts and CDs are good in different ways!
とどのつまり
お通ちゃんは最高ってことだよ！
Either way, Otsu-chan rules!
ねっ 新ちゃん！
Right, Shin-chan?
新ちゃん？
Shin-chan?
隊長どうしたんですか？
今日 なんか元気ないですね｡
Chief, what's wrong?
You seem a little down today.
Considering it was an Otsu-chan concert... Is something wrong?
お通ちゃんのﾗｲﾌﾞだってのに
何か あったんですか？
(新八)そうだな｡
今日はお通ちゃんのﾗｲﾌﾞ｡
You're right.
Today was an Otsu-chan concert.
我々 寺門通親衛隊にとっては
何よりも重要な日｡
The most important day for us members of the Tsu Terakado Fan Club.
A special day that cannot be replaced.
何ものにも代えがたい
特別な日だ なのに｡
And yet...
なんで たった４人しか
集まってねえんだ～!?
Why are there only four of us here?!
ﾎﾞｴｰｯ!!
軍曹！
Sarge!
State the 82nd clause of the Tsu Terakado Fan Club creed!
寺門通親衛隊 隊規82条を
言ってみろ！
Y-You must go to an Otsu-chan concert, even if it's the day of your parents' funeral!
お お通ちゃんのﾗｲﾌﾞは➡
例え 親の葬式の日でも
必ず参加すべし！
ｶｯｺ 姉上の葬式は可 ｶｯｺ閉じ
であります！
Open parentheses. Sis is the exception. Closed Parentheses.
そうだ～！ なのになんだ！
この体たらくは！
That's right!
Yet look at this showing!
他の隊員はどうした!?
What happened to the other members?!
Did you contact everybody?!
ｷｻﾏ！
ちゃんと連絡網は回したのか!?
Y-You've got it wrong, chief!
ち 違うんです 隊長！
Th-This is...
これは これは…！ や や やべ！
ﾊﾞ ﾊﾞｶ！ 軍曹！ お前！
C-Crap...
Y-You idiot, Sarge!
N-No, it's not what you think, Shin-chan.
いやいや 違うんだよ新ちゃん！
これは… その！
やめたのか｡
Th-This is, uh...
They quit?
ｱｲﾂら… まさか｡
Don't tell me...
those guys...
このﾎﾞｸに なんの断りもなく➡
quit...
親衛隊を… やめたのか!?
the fan club...
without asking me?!
ふざけやがって～!!
ﾌﾞｯ殺してやる～!!
Don't give me that shit!
I'll kill them all!
新ちゃん!!
いったい どこのｱｲﾄﾞﾙだ!?
Shin-chan!
Which idol was it?!
どこの腐れｱｲﾄﾞﾙに
鞍替えしやがった!?
Which rotten idol did they switch to?!
お通ちゃん以外のｱｲﾄﾞﾙを
決して崇拝することなかれ！
Did they forget the 14th clause of our creed:
"Ignore any idol who isn't Otsu-chan"?!
隊規14条を 忘れたかﾔﾂら～!!
Shin-chan!
新ちゃん！
落ち着け 新ちゃん!!
C-Calm down, Shin-chan!
落ち着かない！
１人づつ家に乗り込んで➡
I won't calm down!
I'll barge into every single one of their homes
隊規復唱しながら
腕立て伏せだ!!
and make them do push-ups while reciting the club creed!
Y-You've got it wrong, Shin-chan.
(たかちん)ち 違うんだ新ちゃん！
ｱｲﾂら 別に➡
They didn't quit being Otsu-chan's fans by choice!
お通ちゃんのﾌｧﾝを
やめたわけじゃないんだ！
Then why aren't they here?!
じゃあ どうして
ここに来てないんだ!?
What the hell happened?!
いったい
何があったっていうんだ!?
About that!
それは…！
うおぉ～！
Just let it go, Mr. Shimura.
(古田)そのへんにしといて
あげなよ 志村氏｡
(川下)言えるわけないじゃないか｡
(藤山)みんなが出ていったのは➡
We could never tell you.
We didn't leave because of Otsu-chan.
お通ちゃんのせいなんかじゃない｡
(古田)志村氏 ｷﾐのやり方が
気にくわないからだなんて｡
Mr. Shimura, we could never say that we couldn't stand your methods...
Wh-What's with all of you?!
な なんだお前ら！ 気持ﾜﾙｯ!!
You're creeping me out!
古田 川下 藤山！
みんな… ﾃﾒｴらみんな➡
Furuta! Kawashita! Fujiyama!
You're all...
You're all people who quit!
うちをやめてった
連中じゃねえか！
何してやがんだ！
なんだ そのかっこう!?
What are you doing here?!
Don't you feel ashamed to show your face here?!
ﾃﾒｴら 恥ずかしくねえのか!?
You should be the ones to feel ashamed.
恥ずかしいのは ｷﾐたちのほうさ｡
Fan Clubs of hard-line idols are relics of the past
硬派な ｱｲﾄﾞﾙ親衛隊など➡
松田珍子 中森刃牙菜らが
席巻した➡
from the age of Chinko Matsuda and Bakina Nakamori.
太古の昔に
すでに滅んだ前時代の遺物｡
Your methods are old-fashioned.
ｷﾐたちのやり方は
もう古いんだよ｡
そんなやり方では
もう誰もついていかない｡
Nobody will follow you.
寺門通親衛隊は もう滅んだんだ｡
The Tsu Terakado Fan Club has fallen.
これからは そう｡
From now on, yes...
I, I shall lead the new wave...
(ﾄｯｼｰ)このﾎﾞｸ！
ﾎﾞｸが率いるﾆｭｰｳｴｰﾌﾞ｡
The Tsusengumi!
通選組の時代なのだよ ﾌﾟｽｽｽｽ…！
お お前は… ﾄ ﾄｯｼｰ！
Y-You're...
T-Toshi!
ﾌﾟｽｽｽｽ…！
["Any Place with a Bunch of Men Gathered Around Will Turn into a Battlefield"]
うおぉ～!!
(銀時)時は
寺門通ﾌｧﾝｸﾗﾌﾞ戦国時代｡
Our story is set during the Warring Tsu Terakado Fan Clubs Period.
Tsu Terakado had overcome scandal and achieved the position of top idol.
ｽｷｬﾝﾀﾞﾙを乗り越え成長し➡
ついに ﾄｯﾌﾟｱｲﾄﾞﾙの座へと
君臨した 寺門通｡
彼女のもとには
今や無数のﾌｧﾝｸﾗﾌﾞが群雄割拠し➡
Countless numbers of fan clubs engaged in a furious battle for dominance.
日々 熾烈な覇権争いを
繰り広げていた｡
ｵﾌｨｼｬﾙﾌｧﾝｸﾗﾌﾞという
玉爾を賜らんと天下を目指し➡
Men fell in battle as they strived for supreme hegemony, the title of official fan club.
戦い 散っていく男たち｡
死屍累々転がる
そんな戦場にあって➡
On this corpse-riddled battlefield was a group of men considered the strongest.
長きにわたり戦を勝ち抜く
最強の男たちがいた｡
寺門通親衛隊｡
The Tsu Terakado Fan Club.
猛将 志村新八率いる
最強のｵﾀｸたちである｡
The strongest otaku led by their brave general, Shinpachi Shimura!
Veterans among veterans who had supported Tsu Terakado back when she sang on the street.
路上ﾗｲﾌﾞをしていた頃から
寺門通を支えてきた老舗中の老舗｡
親衛隊隊規という
九十九か条にも及ぶ➡
Bound by an ironclad creed numbering 99 clauses,
鉄の掟で縛られた彼らは
恐るべき士気の高さを誇り➡
they had frighteningly high morale and did not know defeat in battle.
戦では負けしらず｡
They dominated every other faction in performance quality, energy, obnoxiousness and lack of women.
ﾊﾟﾌｫｰﾏﾝｽのｸｵﾘﾃｨｰ ﾃﾝｼｮﾝ ｳｻﾞさ
女っけのなさ ｳｻﾞさ➡
どれをとっても他を圧倒していた｡
その歴史の深さからも
ｵﾌｨｼｬﾙに最も近い存在とされ➡
Their long history placed them nearest to the title of official,
幾多の勢力から
攻められ続けてきたが➡
so they were under constant attack from other factions.
猛将 志村に鍛えられた
精強な兵は 崩しがたく➡
But the elite forces trained by the brave general Shimura were difficult to defeat,
かかっていくものは 彼らの前に
死屍を積み重ねるのみだった｡
and the piles of their challengers' corpses grew taller.
形勢 変えがたし｡
It was difficult situation to change.
As many soldiers began laying down their weapons,
次々と武器を捨て
敗走していく兵のなか➡
その男は 戦場に現れた｡
a man appeared.
智将 ﾄｯｼｰ｡
The brilliant general, Toshi!
戦場に流星のごとく現れた彼は
敗走する兵を巧みにまとめあげ➡
He appeared on the battlefield like a shooting star
and cleverly manipulated the deserters into his own faction named the Tsusengumi.
通選組なる組織を結成｡
反発し 戦うことしか
してこなかった他の者とは違い➡
Unlike the others who could only revolt and fight,
彼は 戦うことをしなかった｡
he didn't fight.
ｵﾀｸの心を巧みにつかみ 誘惑し
他勢力を次々に取り込み➡
He understood the workings of the heart of an otaku
and enticed one after another to join from different factions.
瞬く間に最大勢力を築きあげる｡
In no time, he had the largest force of all.
ｱﾆﾒ ﾏﾝｶﾞ ｹﾞｰﾑ 二次元ﾒﾃﾞｨｱから
三次元ﾒﾃﾞｨｱにまで➡
The Tsusengumi he created, which covered everything from
anime, manga, games, and other 2D media to 3D media,
足をのばしてきた彼が
作ろうとする通選組とは➡
お通だけに
とらわれるのではない｡
was not beholden to Otsu.
あらゆるﾒﾃﾞｨｱに通ずる
選ばれたｵﾀｸたちの組織｡
A group of chosen otaku who used all kinds of media.
総合ﾒﾃﾞｨｱｻｰｸﾙとも呼べる
代物であった｡
You could call it a Universal Media Club.
彼の軟弱ともとれる やり方は➡
His methods, considered to be soft-line,
お通しか追いかけてこなかった
硬派な昔気質のｵﾀｸたちに➡
were refreshing to the hard-line, old-fashioned otaku who only followed Otsu.
新鮮な息吹を吹き込む｡
ﾌﾟｽﾌﾟｽ ﾌﾟｽﾌﾟｽ ﾌﾟｽﾌﾟｽ｡
大きく世界を広げていくｵﾀｸ道｡
An otaku creed began to spread.
彼が ｶﾘｽﾏｵﾀｸとして
崇められるのに➡
It didn't take long for him to be considered a charismatic otaku.
そう時間は かからなかった｡
そして そんな彼に
最も魅了されたのは➡
And it goes without saying that the members of the Tsu Terakado Fan Club
鉄の掟で
欲望を抑圧され続けてきた➡
who were forced by ironclad principles to suppress their desires were the first to fall.
寺門通親衛隊であったのは
言うまでもない｡
かつて 彼らを震え上がらせた
猛将 志村の声も➡
They could no longer hear the voice of the brave general Shimura, who once inspired fear in all.
もう彼らの耳には届かない｡
天下統一を目前に
寺門通親衛隊 堕つ｡
Once on the verge of conquering the world,
the Tsu Terakado Fan Club was now on the verge of ruin.
The arrival of a new star led to the curtain falling on this long period of war.
かくして
長きにわたった戦乱の時代は➡
戦場に突如 現れた新星によって
幕を閉じたのだった｡
いやぁ 今週 『銀魂』短っ！
Yeah, this week's GinTama was short...
Why are you ending it already?!
なに 勝手に終わらせてんだ～!!
It's not over!
終わってねえ！ ﾏﾝｶﾞも親衛隊も
まだ終わってねえ！
The manga and fan club aren't over!
How is that okay?!
なにが これでよかったね だよ！
いいわけねえだろ!!
It's obviously not okay!
次号も まったく関係ねえ話
しようとしてんじゃねぇか これ！
And next week's is a totally unrelated story!
This is just your personal wish!
ただの
お前の願望じゃねぇか これ！
That's enough, yeah?
え？ いや もういいだろ｡
これで終わりで いいだろ？
We can end it.
The narration was pretty intense.
ﾅﾚｰｼｮﾝで
かなり盛り上げてやったし…｡
終わるわけねえだろ！
It can't be over!
Only half the episode's been used up!
まだ半分ちょいしか
いってねえんだよ！
How could it end at such a horrible juncture?!
こんな最悪な状況で終われるか!!
もういいよ｡
Just forget it.
どうせ このあと
お前の どうでもいいｸﾞﾁが➡
We'd just have to listen to your eternal bitching.
延々と続くんだろ？
面倒くせぇよ｡ 聞きたくねえよ｡
It's a pain. Don't wanna hear it.
Let it end. I'm begging you.
終わってくれよ 頼むから｡
(神楽)ｱｲﾄﾞﾙとか そんなん
どうでもいいｱﾙ｡
Who cares about idols and whatever?
Go do it by yourself.
勝手にやれよ｡
くだらねぇんだよ 糸くずども！
It's a waste of time, you piece of trash.
そんな言い方しなくても
いいだろ！
You don't have to put it that way!
涙出てくるわ！
ｱﾝﾀらだって知ってるでしょ！
I'm gonna cry!
You should know how much effort I've put into this fan club!
今まで ﾎﾞｸが どれだけ精力的に➡
親衛隊の活動に
取り組んできたか！
How much I love Otsu-chan!
ﾎﾞｸが どれだけ
お通ちゃんを大好きか！
And now, the fan club is on the verge of disbanding!
その親衛隊が 今 壊滅の危機に
瀕してるんですよ｡
After cheering and supporting Otsu-chan this whole time...
今まで ずっと お通ちゃんを
応援し支えてきたのに➡
誰よりも前から！
Before anyone else did!
そのへんからﾊﾟｯと出たﾔﾂに
隊員も地位も奪われ！
And then some random guy shows up and steals my members and status!
お通ちゃんの
ｵﾌｨｼｬﾙﾌｧﾝｸﾗﾌﾞになるという夢も➡
They're trying to steal my dream of becoming Otsu-chan's official fan club!
奪われようとしてるんですよ！
なんてこった｡ まさか
まだあの男が生きていたなんて｡
Unbelievable...
I didn't think that man would still be alive...
もうとっくに消滅しているものと
思っていたのに…｡
I thought he'd been destroyed by now...
いまだ妖刀の呪いは解けず➡
The curse has yet to be broken...
土方さんのなかで
あの男も生き続けていたとは…｡
That man still lived inside of Hijikata-san...
しかも 以前より
数段ｵﾀｸとしてﾊﾟﾜｰｱｯﾌﾟしている！
And he's a suped-up otaku now!
ﾎﾞｸらのような
中途半端なｱｲﾄﾞﾙｵﾀｸが➡
How can some half-assed idol otaku like us compete with that charismatic otaku?
あんなｶﾘｽﾏｵﾀｸに対抗できるのか｡
Do we even stand a chance?!
ﾎﾞｸらに勝ち目はあるのか？
新ちゃん！
Shin-chan!
諦めちゃﾀﾞﾒだ！
まだ勝負はついちゃいねえ｡
You can't give up!
The fight isn't over yet!
The Tsu Terakado Fan Club hasn't died yet!
寺門通親衛隊は
まだ終わったわけじゃねえ！
You still have a member!
隊員なら まだいるじゃねえか！
このｵﾚが！
Right here!
たかちん…｡
まだﾔﾂらに取り込まれてねえ➡
Takachin...
There should still be fan clubs that haven't been absorbed by him!
ﾌｧﾝｸﾗﾌﾞも残っているはず！
Let's join up with them to fight against him!
ｿｲﾂらと
手組んでﾔﾂらに対抗しよう！
We'll show that guy! And the people who betrayed us!
あの野郎と
ｵﾚたちを裏切った連中に➡
目にもの見せてやるんだ！
ｵﾚたちの戦いは これからだ！
Our fight has just begun!
As long as evil exists, their battle will continue.
Forever.
って 終わったんだ 銀魂｡
連載終わらせんな！
And GinTama just ended...
Don't end the series!
Why are you trying to turn this into an incomplete manga?!
何未完で終わった
ﾏﾝｶﾞ風にしたててんだ！
It's true that these endings happen!
確かにあるけども！
こういう終わり方 多いけども！
That most endings are this way!
どこまで
ﾎﾞｸらの話聞きたくないんですか！
But are you that desperate to not hear our story?!
You're going to end the series so you don't have to hear it?!
連載終わらせてまで
聞きたくないんですか！
ｵﾌｨｼｬﾙﾌｧﾝｸﾗﾌﾞとかさ
よくわかんねえよ｡
I don't really understand official fan clubs or the like.
ﾃﾒｴら 何がしたいのか｡
何？ ｵﾌｨｼｬﾙって｡
What are you people trying to do?
What? Official?
勢力争いして ｵﾌｨｼｬﾙになって➡
So you win the war and become official.
その先に
何が待ってるの ｷﾐたちに｡
Then what do you have?
Do you get to go out with Otsu-chan?
お通ちゃんと
つき合えるんですか？
Do you get to kiss Otsu-chan?
お通ちゃんとﾁｭｰできるんですか？
Do you get to **** or XXXX or !@##%%?
…とか …とか …とか
できるんですか？
できねえだろ そんなもん｡
You don't.
Official gets you a couple of biscuits and that's that.
どうせ ﾋﾞｽｹｯﾄ２～３枚もらって
おしまいだよ ｵﾌｨｼｬﾙなんて｡
Hell no! Why biscuits?!
なわけねえだろ！ 何でﾋﾞｽｹｯﾄ！
だったら 今ｵﾚがﾋﾞｽｹｯﾄやるから｡
Then I'll give you some biscuits.
もうそれでいいだろ？
帰れﾊﾞｶ ｵﾌｨｼｬﾙﾊﾞｶ！
Good enough?
Scram, moron. Official moron.
Shut up, moron!
黙れﾊﾞｶ！ ﾋﾞｽｹｯﾄﾊﾞｶ！
ｵﾌｨｼｬﾙﾋﾞｽｹｯﾄﾊﾞｶ！
Biscuit moron!
Official biscuit moron!
Hey, he has no intention of listening to us.
おい 完全に聞く耳ねえよ｡
完全に人間扱いしてねえよ｡
He isn't treating us like fellow humans.
銀さん ｵﾌｨｼｬﾙﾌｧﾝｸﾗﾌﾞとして
認められるってことはね➡
Gin-san, it's a great honor to be acknowledged as the official fan club.
とっても名誉なことなんです｡
今までは ﾎﾞｸらが勝手に一方的に
お通ちゃんを応援してきたけど➡
So far, we've been supporting Otsu-chan one-sidedly,
ｵﾌｨｼｬﾙになるってことはね➡
but if we become official,
that means that Otsu-chan is asking us to cheer for her!
お通ちゃん側から
｢応援してね｣って➡
｢頼りにしてるわ｣って
そういう感じになるわけです！
She'll be depending on us!
Not much difference.
たいして変わんねえだろ｡
変わるんです！
There is!
Our motivation will get a huge boost!
俄然 こっちの
ﾓﾁﾍﾞｰｼｮﾝが変わってくるんです！
要するに
ｵﾌｨｼｬﾙになるってことは➡
Basically, becoming official is like becoming the palace army led by the Shogun!
将軍を介した官軍に
なれるようなもんなんです！
逆に言えば
選ばれなかった者たちは➡
Which means that those who aren't chosen are considered rebels!
ただの賊軍になってしまう！
Could there be a greater dishonor?!
これほど
不名誉なことがありますか！
It's such an aggravating thing to happen after cheering for so long!
今までずっと応援してきたのに｡
そんな
腹立たしいことがありますか！
Then you can just join that group.
じゃあ お前たちも
あっちに入ればいいじゃん｡
そしたら みんな
ｵﾌｨｼｬﾙﾌｧﾝｸﾗﾌﾞの会員になれるｱﾙ｡
Then you can all be members of the official fan club.
We can't join a group with those people!
入れるわけねえだろ！
あんな連中のいるところに！
They're a bunch of traitors and seditionists who encouraged the traitors!
ｵﾚたちを裏切った連中や
裏切りを喚起させた➡
汚ねえ連中の吹きだまりだぜ！
そうだよ！ そもそもｱｲﾂら➡
That's right!
Besides, they're following all kinds of idols besides Otsu-chan!
お通ちゃん以外にもいろんな
ｱｲﾄﾞﾙの追っかけもしてるんだよ！
ﾎﾞｸらのほうが絶対
お通ちゃんを愛してる｡
We're the ones who truly love Otsu-chan!
We're more fit to be official!
ﾎﾞｸらのほうが
絶対 ｵﾌｨｼｬﾙにふさわしい！
あんな連中より下の
会員番号なんてﾎﾞｸはいりません！
I don't need a member number below those freaks!
細けえこと言ってんじゃねえよ｡
Don't be so anal.
同じｹﾂの穴のｸｿだろ｡
お前ら仲よくしろよ｡
It's all the same shit, yeah?
So just get along.
会員番号１番も
100番も変わんねえよ｡
There isn't any difference between member #1 and member #100.
所詮ｱｲﾄﾞﾙにとっちゃ
ﾌｧﾝｸﾗﾌﾞ会員なんて➡
As far as an idol's concerned, fan club members are like smegma.
全員ﾁﾝｶｽみてえなもんなんだから｡
ﾁﾝｶｽＡも ﾁﾝｶｽＺも
変わんねえだろ｡
There isn't any difference between Smegma A and Smegma Z, yeah?
だって ﾁﾝｶｽなんだから｡
'Cause you're still smegma.
If you understand, go make up and drink a liter of soy sauce.
わかったら
さっさと仲直りしに行って➡
全員 仲よく醤油を１ﾘｯﾄﾙ飲め｡
And die, you morons.
そして くたばれ ﾊﾞｶども｡
銀さん…！
Gin-san!
ﾌﾟｽﾌﾟｽﾌﾟｽ
自ら ﾎﾞｸの軍門にくだるのかい？
You're going to voluntarily surrender to my troops?
ﾌﾟｽｽｽ ﾎﾞｸは
一向に構わないんだけど➡
I don't particularly mind,
だが そう慌てずに 状況を
よく見ることをｵｽｽﾒするよ｡
but I recommend that you calm down and reevaluate the situation.
確かに 勢力争いでは
ﾎﾞｸは勝ったが➡
I may have won the battle of size,
but it appears that the title of official isn't something that can simply be won by numbers.
ｵﾌｨｼｬﾙは 数が多ければ
手に入れられる｡
そんな単純なものでは
ないらしいよ｡
Y-You bastard...
ﾃﾒｴ！ よく のこのこ
ここに現れたな｡
How dare you show your face here?!
あの 勝手に人んち
入んないでくんない｡
Uh, could you not walk into someone else's house without permission?
坂田氏 ﾃﾚﾋﾞをつけることを
ｵｽｽﾒするよ｡
Mr. Sakata,
I recommend you turn on the TV.
何なんだよ ｺｲﾂ
人んち勝手に入ってきて➡
What's with this guy?
He walks into somebody else's house without permission and makes recommendations all over the place.
ｵｽｽﾒしまくってんだけど｡
たった今
会見が始まったもようです｡
The interview has just begun.
ﾘﾎﾟｰﾀｰの障子さん｡
(障子)はい ﾘﾎﾟｰﾀｰの障子です｡
We'll go to reporter, Shoji-san.
Yes, this is reporter, Shoji.
たった今 会見が始まりました｡
The interview has just begun.
そうですね 私は➡
Yes...
I love all the people who listen to my songs.
私の歌を聴いてくれる人
みんな大好きだし➡
みんな かけがえのない
大切な人たちだと思ってるから➡
I consider them all irreplaceable.
その あの…｡
Which is why...
そういう大切なﾌｧﾝのみんなに
階級をつけるみたいで➡
I didn't want to assign ranks to my precious fans...
なんか 嫌だったんです
すごくそういうのが｡
I really didn't want that...
だから 今まで こちら側から➡
That's why I tried to avoid having to make such decisions.
そういうのを取り決めるのは
避けてきたんですけど➡
そのせいで ﾌｧﾝの方たちがｹﾝｶとか
いっぱいしてるって聞いて➡
But I heard that my fans were getting into big fights as a result.
So I wasn't sure what I should do.
どうしていいか
わかんなくなっちゃって…｡
そんなときに こちらの
番組さんからお話いただいて➡
That was when this program came to me and asked if I would make a decision.
決めちゃおうかなって｡
ふぅ…｡
寺門通ｵﾌｨｼｬﾙﾌｧﾝｸﾗﾌﾞ
作っちゃいまｽﾄﾛﾝｸﾞ金剛！
I'm going to make a Tsu Terakado official fan club! Strong as a diamond!
Next time on TV Mix-and-match,
The pianist battle to decide Tsu Terakado's official fan club!
Measure of knowledge!
Measure of stamina!
Measure of willpower!
Measure of effort!
Measure of finances!
Measure of Takeuchi!
Measure of influence!
Measure of super powers!
持てる力のすべてを持って叫べ！
Shout out with everything that might make you popular!
お通ちゃんへの愛を！
Scream your love for Otsu-chan!
長きにわたり繰り広げられてきた
男たちの戦いに➡
The long battle between the men
ついに 終止符が打たれる！
will finally be brought to a conclusion!
The pianist battle to decide Tsu Terakado's official fan club.
番組では
出演者を募集しております｡
Our program is seeking applicants.
ﾁｰﾑから ４名 代表者を
選抜のうえ…｡
Each team will be allowed to submit four members.
し 新ちゃん これは…
これは！
Please list your team name, your members' names...
Shin-chan...?
Th-This is...
This is it!
みんな 会場で待ってる
ぞうさんのｳﾝｺ めっさでかい！
Everybody! I'll be waiting on the stage, elephant poop is big!
４名…｡
[ﾓﾆﾀ]優勝ﾁｰﾑには➡
The winners will receive certificates proving them as official fan club members as well as a monetary reward.
Four members...
寺門通ｵﾌｨｼｬﾙﾌｧﾝｸﾗﾌﾞ会員証と
賞金が与えられます｡
ふるって ご応募ください｡
Please send in your applications!
時は 寺門通ﾌｧﾝｸﾗﾌﾞ戦国時代｡
Our story is set during the Warring Tsu Terakado Fan Clubs Period.
熾烈な戦いを勝ち抜き➡
Two tigers managed to survive the furious battle.
最後に戦場に立った２匹の虎｡
寺門通親衛隊と通戦組｡
The Tsu Terakado Fan Club and the Tsusengumi.
その名に ｵﾌｨｼｬﾙを冠するのは
どちらか？
Which will earn the right to be official?!
今 ｵﾀｸたちの最後の戦いが
始まろうとしていた｡
The final battle of the otaku is about to begin!
次号 荒野に獣 慟哭す！
Beasts howl in the wilds!
いや 銀さん
うるさいんですけど｡
Uh, Gin-san, you're really annoying.
最近 ﾊﾏってんですか
ﾅﾚｰｼｮﾝやんの｡
Did you get hooked on the narrating thing?
[To be continued...]
[Preview]
I-If we participate and win, we can still become official!
So we still have a chance!
The next episode...
"If a Friend Gets Injured, Take Him to the Hospital, Stat!"
[The battle for the official Tsu Terakado Fan Club finally begins next week!!]
[5000 people enter! Will Shinpachi's fan club make the cut?!]
[See you next time.]